好啊，抓牢，我要转弯了
All right,hold on. I got to turn up here.
酷吧?
How cool was that?
那可比酷还要厉害
That was way cool.
该我了
My turn.
不行，那可不行
No,sorry,that's not allowed.
就为让你坐在那后面,我刚签了15张表格
I just signed 15 pages of forms,saying you gotta ride on the back of that thing.
我没看见这有律师
I don't see any lawyers around.
你知道不是那意思
You know that's not the point.
不，你只是把乐趣都留给自己罢了
No,you just wanna keep all the fun to yourself.
拜托，爸爸
Come on,dad.
你超过15迈我们就停车,好吧，我认真的
You go over 15,we're pulling over.All right,I mean it.
--你最好了,--好了，上车吧
--You're the best. --All right,get on there.
把护镜带好
Put on your goggles.
抓好离合了么？好儿子
Got the clutch in? All right,that's my boy.
亚当，你速度太快了,慢点
Adam,you're going too fast. Slow it down.
我认真的，你太快了,慢点
I mean it. You're going too fast. Slow down!
亚当
Adam!
放开手闸
Let go of the throttle!
不，亚当，不
No! Adam! No!
什么问题?
what do you got?
16岁，身份验证，卡丁车撞车,40%身体烧伤
16-year-old,status post,atv crash,40% of burns on his body.
肺部插管，给一袋乳酸盐,敞开套管
Nasotracheal intubation.Start a bag of lactated ringer's wide open.
他会没事么?
Is he gonna be okay?
等会儿我们跟你说,把他弄出去
We'll be with you when we can.Get him out.
等等
Wait,wait,wait.
我开始输液了,来，挪一下他
I'll start fluids.Let's go get him moved up.
De-re-maki.De-re-maki.
找你呢
Been looking for you.
躲着你呢，烧伤科能处理
Been avoiding you. Burn unit can handle it.
如果他们能处理,他们就不用找你了
If they could handle it,they wouldn't be asking for you.
那是杂志么?
Is that a journal?
一个朋友写了篇文章
A friend wrote an article.
用北印度语?
In hindi?
在印度他们有类似神经系统科学规划
They have a cutting edge neuroscience program in india.
在封面上说的不错
Says so right on the cover.
这小子的心律混乱
This kid's heart rate's messed.
烧伤可以解释心动过速
Tachycardia can be explained by the burn.
我猜烧伤科知道这个
I assume the burn unit knew that.
他钾低
His potassium's low.
也可以用烧伤解释
Which can also be explained by the burn.
只是我肯定烧伤科会给他输液
Except I'm sure the burn unit's pumping him with fluids,
所以他的钾该高而不是低
which means his potassium should be going up,not down.
可能是安非他明
Could be amphetamines.
或者是心脏有细菌
Or bacteria lunching on his heart.
或者是先天性心肌炎,类似的坏事
Or cardiomyopathy,or some other very bad thing.
他需要EKG
he needs an ekg.
好吧，没有皮肤，没有EKG
Okay,no skin,no ekg.
他到底能不能从烧伤恢复啊?
Is he even going to survive the burn?
你有约会么?
You got a date or something?
40%的身体
40% of his body.
如果烧伤科能防止感染
If the burns unit can prevent an infection,
他的身体能再生10%
his body will regenerate maybe 10%.
外科移皮20%
Surgeon's will do 20 or so grafts.
就在这个房间，6个月的功夫,他会弄上一身丑陋的疤
Six months in this room,he'll end up with a series of nasty scars.
也许会疼，但他能活
maybe some pain,but he'll live.
除非他的心脏罢工了,因为我们没有发现
Unless his heart shuts down,because we can't figure out
钾低和心动过速的原因
what's causing the low potassium and tachycardia.
我们需要一位比利时医生的帮助,他叫安索芬
We need help from a belgian doc,named einthoven.
他死了
He's dead.
在他活着的时候,他发明了一个小东西叫检流计
While he was alive,he invented a little ditty called the galvanometer.
我们上哪去弄?
Where do we get one?
去任何一家从1905年就开的电子商店
Go to any electronics store that's been open since before 1905.
没准他们在地下室的角落里就有一个
There's a good chance they got one in the corner in the basement.
我们要设立一个声频/视频讲堂
we need an audio/visual setup for the lecture hall.
为什么?
What for?
讲座啊
For the lecture.
什么讲座?
What lecture?
韦伯博士的讲座
Dr. Weber's lecture.
谁是韦伯博士?
Who's dr. Weber?
哦，神经学者，我想
Uh,neurologist,I think.
备忘录是打你这来的
The memo was from you.
我的助手在哪?
Where's my assistant?
她走了
She left.
什么时候?
When?
周三
Wednesday.
真的吗?
Seriously?
临时工介绍所给介绍了一个,可她走丢了
The temp agency sent someone,but she got lost.
等她到的时候把她炒了
Well,when she gets here,fire her.
是你发的这个备忘录么?
Did you issue this memo?
看那个
Look at that.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
昏迷了两年的病人
The patient that has been in a coma for two years
依然昏迷
and counting is still in a coma.
这不是我的签字
This is not my signature.
我不知道有关这个家伙的事情
I don't know anything about this guy.
我需要介绍他吗? 吃午饭?
I'm supposed to introduce him? Have lunch?
昏迷病人偏头疼?
The coma patient has a migraine?
哦，不，不，我给他药,弄出来偏头疼
Oh,no,no.I gave him medication to prevent a migraine.
那是偏头疼,增加了他脑动脉的流动速率
That's a migraine.increased flow velocity in his cerebral arteries.
我干的，后来，给他硝酸甘油
I did,subsequently,give him nitroglycerin,which could possibly
你给一个昏迷病人引发偏头疼?
you induced a migraine headache in a coma patient?
我让他头疼
I gave him a little headache.
跟你现在给我的差不多
Similar to the one you're giving me now.
你是否读过伦理规章啊?
Have you even read an ethical guideline?
如果在有痛感的人身上尝试
Well,it'd be wrong to try out a new migraine prevention
防止疼痛的药物是不对的
medication on someone who can actually feel pain.
这是你签的吗?
Did you sign this?
我们一会儿再谈学科的规章吧
We can talk later about the appropriate discipline.
因为烧伤
because of the burn,
我们无法进行常规检查探究问题
we can't perform any of our normal tests to see what's wrong.
所以我们要试用检流计
So we're going to try a galvanometer.
他可以由手腕和脚踝提取脉搏
It picks up a pulse in the wrists and the ankles.
希望能知道为什么他的心律失常
Hopefully it will tell us why his heart rhythm is abnormal.
我到底是怎么害了他啊，我--
What have I done to him.I--
是事故
it was an accident.
好了，所以，他烧了这么多伤
All right,so... he's got all these burns.
然后他的心脏还有问题?
And now there's something wrong with his heart?
我们在尝试找出这两者之间的关联
We're trying to figure out if the two are somehow connected.
他最近生病了吗?
Had he been sick lately?
没有
No,nothing.
任何非常态的举动？很疲乏？
Anything unusual with his behavior?Had he been tired a lot?
没有，他很好，很快乐
Nothing.He was great.He was happy.
他当时很开心，然后……
He was just having a great time and then--
如果他用过安非他明或可卡因…
if he was experimenting with amphetamines or cocaine--
没有,一年前我们给了他些大麻尝尝
no.We gave him some pot about a year ago to try.
就一次
It was just once.
我们认为如果让他知道毒品的神秘
We thought if we took the mystery out of drugs and alcohol,
他就不会好奇了
the less he'd experiment.
试验后我们会知道
We'll know more after the tests.
看上去他们象要给他施电刑一样
It looks like they're gonna electrocute him.
插进去吧
Plug it in.
你插
You plug it in.
好，给我电线
Fine. Gimme the cord.
有效的
Works.
U型线明显
Prominent u-waves.
没有反转的T型线，没有缺血症状
No inverted t-wave.no ischemia.
q型线正常
q-wave normal.
那可不好
That's not good.
关掉，关掉
Turn it off. Turn it off!
发生什么事？怎么了？
What's happening?What is that?
他抽筋了，进来
he's seizing,get in here.
谁给我的病人施电刑了?
who electrocuted my patient?
他抽搐
He had a seizure.
没人给他施电刑
he wasn't electrocuted.
抽搐告诉我们什么？走开
What does the seizure tell us?Move.
你找什么?
What are you looking for?
跟你一样，爱和接纳
Same as you. Love,acceptance.
付出有所收获
Solid return on investments.
鉴别诊断，开始
Differential diagnosis. Go.
可能是癫痫或者是抽搐失调
Could be epilepsy,or seizure disorder.
那样不会心动过速,可能是脑部有病毒
Not with the tachycardia. It could be a virus in his brain.
厉害，肾上腺分泌失调
Specificity's impressive. adrenoleukodystrophy.
可能是M.S.
Could be M.S.
抽搐可能由脑部外伤所致
Seizures could be caused by plaques and lesions on the brain.
好，我们来找找吧，给他做核磁共振
Well,let's find out which. Get him an mri.
没有核成像
No nuclear imaging.
他受不了往放射科搬
He wouldn't survive the move to radiology.
核磁共振跟ct都不行了
Mri and ct scan are both out.
好，腰椎穿刺能说明问题,如果他的蛋白质提高的话
Okay.Lumbar puncture'll tell us if his proteins are elevated.
至少可以排除 M.S.
At least we can exclude M.S.
不能做腰椎穿刺
Can't do a lumbar puncture either.
你在妨碍我退场
You're cramping my exits.
别跟我说他的脊骨上没有皮肤
Don't tell me,no skin on his spine.
我们会把针头扎进个满是细菌的地方
We'd be inserting a needle into an area that's teeming with bacteria.
如果目前他还没有脑感染,那我们会帮他染上
If he doesn't have a brain infection already,we'd give him one for sure.
那就没有观察大脑的方法了
There's no other way to look at a brain.
转录多普超声波检查
Transcranial doppler sonography.
她说的是大脑，不是孕妇的子宫
She said brain,not pregnant woman's uterus.
听上去挺象
They do sound alike.
我今天早上用过来观察病人大脑
I used one to look at a brain this morning.
那你干嘛不带病人,做放射检查或者是核磁共振？
Why didn't you take the patient to radiology,get an mra?
很显然，我在做非法的事
Obviously,I was doing something illegal,
而用核检查方式会提高被质询的可能
and using nuclear imaging would've raised questions.
你无法从语图上得到MS的诊断
You're not gonna get a diagnosis of M.S. From a sonogram.
不是决定性的，可有M.S.的病人
Not definitively,but patients with M.S.
在枕叶皮层会有更多的神经反应
Have more reactive neurons in their occipital cortex.
好
Okay
谢谢你们今天光临韦伯博士的讲座
Thank you for all coming to today's lecture by dr. Phillip weber,
他是我们医院今天的客人,讲有关头疼的话题
who is our guest today at our hospital to talk about headaches.
韦伯博士在韦伯疼痛中心,这倒是有道理
Dr. Weber is at the weber center for pain. That makes sense.
韦伯，韦伯,让我们欢迎韦伯博士
Weber-weber.So please welcome,dr. Weber.
谢谢，卡迪医生
Thank you,doctor...cuddy.
我认为我该多告诉,你们一些关于我的情况
I suppose I should tell you a little bit more about myself.
我在弗吉尼亚上学
I went to school in virginia
你从不来这样的地方，他到底是谁?
you've never to one of these things in your life. Who is this guy?
不知道
No idea.
你穿的这个样干嘛?
What's with the outfit?
灵光闪现，寒气袭人，无法名状
Sudden chills,and light sensitivity.Inexplicable.
我在霍普金斯大学得到了医学学历
I received my medical degree at johns hopkins university,
我跟布曼和季马学习
where I studied under brightman and gilmar.
他肯定不错，你上的霍普金斯,师从布曼和季马
he must be good. You went to hopkins and studied under brightman and gilmar.
在马由诊所得了道尔奖
helped me win the doyle internship at the mayo clinic.
你本该得道尔奖的
You were supposed to get the doyle internship.
这家伙是万.里博曼,把你以欺诈为理由赶出去的家伙？
This guy's von lieberman? The guy got you thrown out for cheating?
是院长赶走我的
The dean threw me out.
万.里博曼不过是告密的
Von lieberman just ratted on me.
这家伙叫韦伯，不是万.里博曼
This guy's name is weber,not von lieberman.
我把他韦伯叫成万.里博曼,很邪恶
I call weber von lieberman.Way eviler. ...
而接收器
and the receptors have
改良了偏头疼的敏感度
improved the acute treatment of migraines.
根据这点...
To this point...
那你的计划呢?
so what's the plan?
你要等他鞠躬的时候放屁吗?
You wanna wait 'til he bends over and make a fart sound?
我不是要在这算旧账的
I'm not here about the past.
他是个坏科学家
He's a bad scientist.
是你骗了他，他能有多坏?
Well,you cheated off him,how bad can he be?
他的答案是错的
He got the answer wrong.
他们是要唤醒他吗?
are they trying to wake him up?
他们不能那样，对吗？,那样太疼了
They can't do that,right? He'll be in too much pain.
别担心，他还没醒呢
Don't worry,he's still under.
但大脑并没完全睡，总是工作的
But the brain never completely sleeps,it's always working.
控制你的心跳、呼吸和温度
Controlling your heart rate. Breathing. Temperature.
眼睛会对视像做出反应
The eyes respond to visual stimuli.
血流会在大脑的特定部位加速流动
Blood flow increases in certain areas of the brain
然后我们可以用语图来追踪
and we can track that with a sonogram.
M.S.会使血管内部流动加快
With M.S.,Blood vessels are more reactive,so flow is faster.
如果亚当受了感染
If adam has an infection,
会有积水压迫动脉
there'd be swelling which would constrict the arteries,
流动就会减慢
and the flow would be slower.
小蔡，靠近蛛网膜下
Chase,near the subarachnoid space.
控制主题的数据由双向分析
Data from control subjects were analyzed with a two-way anova
借主题的事实之旁证证明
with status and side as within-subject factors.
你追踪了这家伙20年,就为了给他点羞辱？
You stalked this guy for 20 years just for the shot to humiliate him?
我在学习
I'm trying to learn.
无反弹的管路
...Vessels without significant rebound.
他甚至不知道那是什么
He doesn't even know what that means.
你要打断他，是吧?
You're going to interrupt him,aren't you?
如果我有问题的话
If I have a question.
那怎么实现呢?
And what's that going to accomplish?
你不能好好享受么?
Why can't you just enjoy this?
你怎么就不能为我高兴呢?
Why can't you just be happy for me?
你得找个比羞辱人,少削弱你精力的宣泄方式
You have got to find less debilitating outlets than humiliating people.
我听说保龄球挺好
I hear bowling is more fun than stalking.
可我干这个更在行
But I'm better at this.
如果P比零点少...
If p is less than point zero...
在等离子电视上花点钱
blow a ton of money on a plasma tv.
我们发现了一处蛛网膜下出血
We found a subarachnoid bleed.
头部的出血不会导致抽搐
Bleed in the head isn't causing seizures.
有可能，10%的大脑皮层损伤会抽搐
It could be.10% with damage to the cerebral cortex have seizures.
或是细菌性脑膜炎
Or bacterial meningitis.
病毒性脑炎?
Viral encephalitis?
无法知道……
There's no way to tell without--
闭嘴
shut up!
对不起?
Excuse me?
不是你
Not you.
如果我的讲座打扰了你们的会议,我可以等
If my lecture is interrupting your meeting,I can wait.
象你们印度人说的，多谢了
As your people say in india.Appreciate it.
我们一会儿琢磨原因,止血，要不会死人的
We'll figure out why later.Fix the bleed,or he dies.
几小时后见
Talk to you in a couple of hours.
我在蛛网膜下部位了
I'm in the subarachnoid space.
能弄好吗?
Can you get it?
差不多吧
I think so.
把探针撤回来，让我看见线
Put the probe back where it was so I can see the wire.
我们在找出血点
We're looking for the bleed--
没有对比ct，我简直是在盲飞,帮我看着点
look when I get there!I'm flying blind without a contrast ct here.
当P不到0.001时
And with a p value of less than 0.001,
我们有强有力的证据显示,这个药带来偏头疼
we have strong statistical evidence that this drug prevents migraine ,headaches
不必日常摄取
without daily administration.
哦，对不起，医生
Uh,excuse me,doctor.
他比你在这个领域更在行
He knows this field better than you do.
我一直理解
It's always been my understanding that
除非日常摄取,否则没有药物能导致偏头疼
unless you follow a daily regimen,no drug can prevent a migraine.
所以才叫它突破
That's why they call it a breakthrough.
所以你才叫它突破
That's why you call it a breakthrough.
不，药物公司支持在我的诊所试验
No,the pharmaceutical company sponsoring my clinical trials
也觉得是突破
also hails it as a breakthrough.
我肯定你妻子跟律师也觉得是
I'm sure your wife and lawyer do too.
有人会在替自己赚大钱的东西面前
Is there anybody who doesn't stand to make a fortune from it,
不管它叫突破的吗？
calling it a breakthrough?
你是谁?
Who are you?
只是个极度需要个人爱好的疯子
Just a lunatic who desperately needs a hobby.
你到底是怎么做试验的?
How exactly do these studies work?
你把药给一群人
Do you give this drug to a bunch of people
他们没了偏头疼,齐活，你的药就有效了?
and they don't get a migraine,you go,voila,my drug works?
请原谅，小姐?
Excuse me,miss?
你有癌症吗?
Do you have cancer?
芒果汁可致癌
Mango juice prevents cancer.
或许这个讲座前我该吃我的药
Perhaps I should've taken my medication before this lecture.
我们有很精确的试验小组
We had a very specific control group.
慢性偏头疼的受害者
Chronic migraine sufferers.
我至今还没看完所有的数据
I don't have time to go through all the math right now,
但影响范围引人注目
but the incidence was dramatically--
没错，在印度
sure,in india.
在那2加2等于5，是吧?
Two plus two equals five there,right?
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
我知道你的计算技术，很差劲
I know your math skills.They blow.
天哪
Touch?
你口音很熟
You sound very familiar.
为什么你要去印度,那样晦暗的杂志发表?
Why did you publish it in an obscure journal in india?
为什么不在
Why not publish in
南费城很酷的地方发表?
really really cool head cases of south philly?
新德里神经科学是很受推崇的杂志
Neuroscience new delhi is a respected journal.
连说n都卡壳的家伙说那是最好的杂志
The guy running slurp 'n' gulp tells me it's one of the best.
找个地缝吧，随便什么
Get a hooker.Anything.
你看，我想
See,I'm thinking that
发表著作或许是
publishing studies is probably the easiest way
引制药公司上钩的最早办法
to get a pharmaceutical company to give you a reach-around.
而找个没人会读的杂志
And choosing a journal that no one can actually read,
是很，很精明的
well,that's,that's shrewd.
我知道我认识你
I know I know you.
当然你认识，呆子
Sure you do. Dick.
我叫菲利普
My name's philip.
哦，我错了，是你脸的事
Oh,my bad.Something to do with your face.
我一直觉得你的名字是呆子
I always think your name is dick.
豪斯?
House?
是
Here.
医学院是20年前的事
Medical school was 20 years ago.
拜托，长大吧
Give it a rest,grow up.
你一直都是成年人，做负责任的事
You were always the grown-up,do the responsible thing.
--告密的,--你欺骗
--Tattletale. --You cheated.
我那时欺骗，而你现在欺骗
I cheated then,you're cheating now.
你的药没用
Your drug doesn't work.
对，你当然想那么相信
Yes,you would like to believe that,
因为符合你的白日梦
because it plays right into your fantasy--
我试过
I tested it.
哦，真的？你的参数是什么？,你的专著呢？
Oh,really?What are your parameters? Where's your study?
2134房
Room 2134.
一个病人?
One patient?
昏迷病患?
The coma patient?
你一点都没改
You haven't changed a bit.
你当年在医学院走捷径,现在你还走捷径
You took short cuts in med school,you're taking short cuts now.
你不能在一个非常态的大脑尝试
You cannot test this on an abnormal brain.
真封闭
That's so closed-minded.
他不是非常态，他很特别
He's not abnormal,he's special.
昏迷的病人大脑皮层萎缩
Cerebral cortex atrophies in coma patients.
你需要活的有意识的病人
You need live,conscious people.
你不是万事通，豪斯
You don't know everything,house.
那是什么东西阻断了大脑的功能
it's something that disrupts brain function.
插片很好，阻断神经传递
Plaques are perfect. Interrupt neuronal communication.
M.S.?
没有M.S.就复杂了,我觉得是基础问题
No.M.S. Is complicated. I think this is more basic.
只是心动过速和抽搐
It's just tachycardia and seizures.
烧伤科的人还要把他关里头多长时间?
How much longer the burn unit guys gonna keep him in that thing?
讲座结束了，走吧，豪斯想……
Lecture's over. Let's go.House wants to...
亚当醒了
adam's waking up.
把麻醉科的叫进来
Get the anesthesiologist in here now.
他疼
he's in pain.
不是疼
That's not pain.
需要帮助这里
Need some help in here.
亚当来高潮了
Adam had an orgasm.
什么?你意思是当他……天啊!
What?You mean while he was--God!
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我偏头疼
I'm having a migraine.
你有事吗?
Are you okay?
我是对的
Yes. I was right.
我得把你麻倒几个小时
I'm gonna knock you out for a couple of hours.
不行，我有事要做，给我点止疼的
No,I got work to do.Just gimme sumatriptan for the pain
和异博定确保它不复发就行了
and verapamil so it doesn't recur.
我听说病人在高压氧仓挺乐和？
I heard the patient had fun in the hyperbaric chamber.
得安排我自己进去试试
Gotta schedule me some time in there.
韦伯的药在美国还不合法
Weber's meds aren't even legal in the U.S.
在印度合法，不明所以
It's legal in india.I was disoriented.
来回动不好
Moving around is a bad idea.
嘿，如果你胸疼，告诉我
Hey,if you feel chest pain,you need to let me know.
异搏定可导致心脏充血困难
Verapamil can cause congestive heart failure.
无物可伤我心
Nothing can hurt my heart.
嘿，你会觉得头晕的
Hey,you're gonna feel some dizziness.
肯定会便秘
Definitely gonna be constipated.
射精的鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis for getting off.
他会没事吗?
Is he gonna be okay?
不会，他很有问题
No,something's seriously wrong with him.
射精的鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis for ejaculation.
别让我再说了
Don't make me say it again.
我们没拖延，只是不知道
We're not stalling,we just don't know.
那就猜啊
Then guess.
止疼药会导致射精吗?
Could pain medication cause an orgasm?
我希望
I wish.
也许是疼痛导致高潮
Maybe pain caused the orgasm.
你画纹身，大脑释放安多芬,制造欣快
You get a tattoo,the brain releases endorphins which create pleasure.
大多数人不会因针刺而高潮
Most people don't orgasm from a needle prick.
小蔡说的有理
well,chase has a point.
大脑象个大车站，如果车闸……
The brain is like a huge train station.If the switches--
你是神经学家，替我说吧
You're the neurologist,talk for me.
如果感官信息被前脑神经束曲解
If sensory information got misinterpreted by the medial forebrain bundle,
会导致好感觉是坏，坏感觉是好
it's possible for bad to feel good and good to feel bad.
他是个走运的小子,我们等他烧伤在治疗他吧
He's a lucky kid.Let's not fix him until the burns heal.
那么是什么攻击了前脑神经束?
So what attacks the medial forebrain bundle?
传染神经炎，脉管神经炎
Infective neuropathies. Vasculitic neuropathies.
妄想症，脑蛋白营养不良
Krabbe's disease,metachromatic leukodystrophy.
都是坏事
all very bad things.
在他的条件都不会发生
No way to look for any of them in his condition.
可能是感染
Could be an infection.
我8秒钟前刚说完感染
I said infection about eight seconds ago.
你列举的是脑部感染
You listed some brain infections.
但如果只是普通的,烧伤皮肤溃烂感染呢?
But what if it's just a regular old infection festering in the burned skin?
用手臂做超声试验,并不会导致前脑问题
Pus on his arm isn't causing problems in the forebrain.
他用了20种药物控制疼痛和心脏
He's on 20 different medications to manage his pain,his heart,
他小便多久一次？
how often he urinates.
他的大脑象个跑堂的……
His brain is like a waiter that's got too many--
我才能做隐喻
I do the metaphors.
脑部遭重压
The brain is stressed.
感染会导致他滑出边缘
An infection elsewhere could put it over the edge.
那我们就等他烧伤好了,再看你是否正确?
So we just wait for his burns to heal to see if you're right?
如果你错了，他没有那个时间
If you're wrong,he doesn't have that kind of time.
多拉力
Dominic larrey.
另一个死医生?
He another dead doctor?
他是拿破仑的首席医生
He was napoleon's surgeon in chief.
清理过很多战争外伤
Cleaned a lot of battle wounds.
切除腿
By amputating legs.
有很多虫子
And with bugs.
蛆能直接进入亚当的烧伤
Maggots are implanted directly into adam's burns.
蛆吃死人……
Maggots--eat dead people. I--
蛆吃死肉，只吃死肉
maggots eat dead flesh. Only dead flesh.
所以他们绝对适合清理伤口
So they're perfectly suited to clean wounds.
它们同时会杀死,在受伤组织里滋生的细菌
They also kill the bacteria that thrive in injured tissues.
杰力博士，我猜他们发现了,动物园里被吃了一半的羊
Dr. Jekyll,I presume,they found a half-eaten sheep in the zoo.
警察要问你些问题
The police want to ask you a few questions.
我需要些东西把它冲下去
I need something to wash it down.
咖啡？不好，最好别用水
Coffee?Bad idea.You're better off with water!
咖啡很接近
Coffee's closer.
很简便的计划，顺便一提
Foolproof plan,by the way.
要不就是他的药有效,而你精神疼痛
Either his meds would work,and you'd be in psychic pain,
因为魔鬼万会很富有
because von evil is gonna be rich.
或他们无效，那你一天可要受罪了
Or they wouldn't,and you get to be in agony all day.
双输局面，典型的你
Perfect lose/lose situation. Very you.
我得证明……
I had to prove--
你什么也没证明
you proved nothing.
对，这不是偏头疼
Right. This isn't a migraine.
对，亲爱的英国医药杂志
Yeah,dear new england journal of medicine,
我吃了这个家伙的药，可还是头疼
I took this guy's drug,and still got a headache.
因而用科学的方法,证明了你的宿敌是个傻子
Thus scientifically proving that my arch enemy is an idiot.
你就是想要疼
You just wanted the pain.
那个药该可以预防偏头疼
The meds are supposed to prevent migraine.
你别疼搞乱了
You get distracted by pain.
让你该考虑的事情变得没有空间
Leaves less room for the things you don't wanna think about.
比如航空公司可恶，汽油的价钱
Like the flyers sucking,or the price of gas,or
面对你把爱推出了你的生命
the fact that you pushed the love of your life out of your life.
上帝，我真希望疼痛消失
God,I wish the pain would go away.
下次当你想把她赶走的时候,拿个针头戳进眼睛里吧
Next time you need to get your mind off her,stick a needle in your eye.
那时你能走也不会给我们带来不快
It's less annoying to the rest of us when you can still walk.
你睡这了么?
did you sleep here?
低点
Lower.
你要枕头么?
Do you want a pillow?
不是轻，是低,你声音的频率刺耳
Not softer,lower.The frequency of your voice is grating.
到这会儿，你该好了
You should've been better by now.
我是超人，病人?
I'm super. The patient?
蛆把烧伤弄的不错
Maggots did great for the burn.
但脑波还是到处都是
But the brainwaves are still all over the map.
也就是说你的普通感染,并没导致他的脑部功能紊乱
Which means your regular old infection isn't causing his brain dysfunction.
也就是说有潜在条件
Which means there's an underlying condition.
所以我们得进入他的头
Which means we gotta get inside his head.
做腰椎穿刺
Do a lumbar puncture.
我们已经确定不能做……
We've already established that we can't get a lumbar--
2节，3节
c2,c3.
不，不行
No,no,no way.
我只一次看到过一节的,会把那家伙搞瘫痪
I only saw a cervical tap once,and that guy got paralyzed.
问父母是想让他儿子坐轮椅,还是死掉
Ask the parents if they prefer to have their son in a wheelchair,or dead.
某事使他大脑失控
Something's causing his brain to lose control.
最终会导致关闭
Eventually it will shut off.
得做腰椎穿刺
We need to do a lumbar puncture
获取脊液用来诊断
to get some of the fluid in his spine so we can test it.
你要我们签同意书?
You need us to sign a consent?
我得警告你们
I have to warn you.
有高风险可导致瘫痪或死亡
There's a serious risk of paralysis or death.
你是说我们不该做么?
Are you saying we shouldn't do this?
我们需要做
You have to do this.
那你们干嘛告诉我可能出问题?
Then why are you telling us what can go wrong?
我觉得你该知道
I just think you should know.
要么就是你们很残忍,要么就是这个签字板
Either you're cruel or this clipboard is a way for you to cover your ass
在万一你们把我儿子搞成瘸子后,给你们退路
in case you cripple our son.
这不是他的错……
This isn't his fault--
不，不是，是你的错,这是你一直告诉我的
no,it's not,it's yours. That's what you keep telling me.
我儿子躺在里面半死不活
My son is lying in there half dead.
我在找条可以熬过去的路
I am just trying to find a way to get through this.
－对不起,－是，我知道
I'm sorry. Yeah,I know.
针
Needle.
--没进去,--别用蛮力
--It's not going in. --Don't force it.
我要往上点
I'm going one space higher.
那太靠近脑干了,会出疝气
It's too close to his brain stem,it'll herniate.
你会把他搞瘫痪
You're gonna paralyze him.
没帮助
Not helping.
他血压飚升，停止
His blood pressure's spiking.Stop.
我能做到
I can get it.
180/120，会中风
He's 180 over 120. He's gonna stroke.
我进去了，给我小瓶子
I'm in the space.Gimme the vial.
他没得ms，或感染
He doesn't have M.S. Or an infection.
他的蛋白质没提高?
His proteins aren't elevated?
蛋白质错了，Igm,不是igg
Wrong protein. Igm,not igg.
上升可能由出血导致
Elevation was probably caused by the bleeding.
如果在他撞车前有麻刺的感觉呢？
What if there was tingling in his extremities prior to the crash?
怎么还是M.S.?
How can you still be on M.S.?
得追症状啊
You gotta be on something.
有东西妨碍了他的神经活动,比如损伤
Something's interrupting his neurons' chit-chat. Like lesions.
我们无法扫描
We can't scan for them.
唯一能做的试验我们已经做了,而且是阴性的
Only test we can do we just did,and it was negative.
他即无麻刺感，也不麻木
He has no tingling,no numess.
你看了他的病史,父母没说什么
You read his history.Parents didn't say anything--
那亚当呢?
what about adam?
我们不能看他的大脑,可你要求我们读他的思维么？
We can't look into his brain,but you want us to read his mind
说的好
Good point.
你们很快可以继续给他洗澡
You can finish the sponge bath in a minute.
他们只是在给他敷药
They're just redoing his dressings.
他没知觉，很好
He's out,he's fine.
我不是找你把他弄晕
I didn't page you to put him out,
我找你把他弄醒
I paged you to wake him up.
这些等这么亮干嘛?
Why are these lights so damn bright?
谢谢
Thank you.
快点，我要跟他说话
Come on,I need to talk to him.
豪斯，你不能唤醒一个烧伤病人,玩20个问题的游戏
House,you can't wake up a burn victim to play 20 questions.
那是折磨
It's torture.
他不会记得
He won't remember.
他会疼的要死
He's gonna be in extraordinary pain--
上帝，你真好，你让我想睡觉
god,you're good. You're putting me to sleep.
我知道他会疼
I know he's gonna be in pain,
我知道你不喜欢，我是他的主治,把他弄醒
I know you disapprove,I'm his attending,wake him up.
哦，天啊
oh,my god.
我是豪斯医生
I'm dr. House.
很疼
It hurts!
会越来越坏，所以快回答
It's gonna get a lot worse,so answer fast.
在车祸前……
Before the accident,
你是否感到麻木和麻刺的感觉?
did you experience any numbness any tingling in your fingers?
你被烧伤了，正在康复,我需要答案
You got burnt,it's healing,I need an answer.
太疼了
It really hurts!
腿或手是否麻木?
Any tingling in your arms or legs?
做点什么？我不能……
Do something! I can't--
亚当，你听我说,你感到什么了么?
adam,you gotta listen to me. Did you feel anything?
我尿裤子了，然后……,我不记得了
I pissed my pants and then i don'T...remember--
他没事么?
Is he okay?
把所有人集中到我办公室
Get everyone in my office.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
小子叫唤让我头疼,我得吃个阿司匹林
Kid's screaming gave me a headache. I gotta take an aspirin.
豪斯，你没事么？,我们在等你
House.You okay?We've been waiting for you.
我有幻觉
I'm hallucinating.
偏头疼有幻觉很罕见
Hallucinations with migraines are pretty uncommon.
你看见什么?
What'd you see?
我看见音乐
I saw music.
感官欺诈没有道理
Sensory deception makes no sense.
你吃了什么
You took something.
那孩子在为生命作战
The kid's fighting for his life.
嘿，你找到他了么?
hey,you find him?
他在衣帽间幻觉呢
He was hallucinating in the locker room.
他没事么?
He okay?
他不觉得疼，在high
He's feeling no pain,he's high.
力固定 high?
Vicodin high?
过去那个了，他正在看音乐,吃了什么
Past that. He's seeing sounds. Took something.
这里怎么这么黑，外面很美
why is it so dark in here?Beautiful day outside.
打开窗帘,让阳光进来
Open the shades. Let the sunshine in.
现在是夜里
It's nighttime.
还是周二，是吧?
It's still tuesday,right?
你看上去不错
You look better.
我吃了什么
I took something.
介意我问是什么么?
Mind if I ask what?
这一点，那一点
little of this,little of that.
我知道病人怎么了,他抑郁
I know what's wrong with our patient.He's depressed.
你叫醒他时他告诉你的么?
He told you that when you woke him up?
不，他说他尿裤子后,就昏过去了
No,he told me he pissed his pants and blacked out.
那不是抑郁的诊断
That's not a diagnostic of depression.
胃口萎缩，孤立自己
Lack of appetite. Isolating yourself--
不能控制排尿，昏迷是什么的症状？
uncontrollable urination and blackingut are good predictors of what?
抽搐
Seizure.
那就证明他所患的抽搐
Which means the seizure he had when you
包括你测试他心脏的时候,那是第二次
tested his heart was at least his second seizure.
那又怎样？,抑郁和抽搐没有关联
So what? Depression and seizures aren't correlated.
你知道什么有关联?
No,but you know what is?
抑郁和抗抑郁药
Depression and anti-depression medicine.
氧化屏显正常
Tox screen was clean.
可你知道他用了多少药对抗烧伤么？
But you know how much crap he's got in his system for dealing with those ,burns
那家伙能让整个西班牙舰队,在他的血流里倾覆
The guy could have the spanish armada floating through his bloodstream,
我们不会知道，直到他们开始开炮
we wouldn't know about it,'til they started firing cannons.
抗抑郁药已知可导致少儿抽搐,但不是高潮
Antidepressants have been known to cause seizures in kids,but not orgasms.
这是有毛病的大脑
This is a brain in trouble.
这个是血液有复合胺的大脑
This is a brain with too much serotonin.
复合胺影响情绪和胃口
Serotonin affects mood,appetite.
不会导致大脑关闭
It doesn't cause a brain to shut down.
抗抑郁药会让大脑觉得
Antidepressants fake brains into thinking
他们有比实际多的复合胺
they have more serotonin than they actually do.
每千万病例会发生连锁反应
Every 10 million or so cases,it sets off a chain reaction.
能产生足够麻烦
It produces too much,enough to fry itself.
如果亚当有复合胺就死定了
If adam has serotonin storm,it's deadly.
但可以治疗，二苯环哽锭
But treatable.Cyproheptadine.
除非他真有复合胺
Unless he doesn't have serotonin storm.
比起复合胺，他会更容易有多巴胺
He could just as easily have too much dopamine as serotonin.
可如果是多巴胺,二苯环哽锭会杀死他
But if it's dopamine,the cyproheptadine will kill him.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
我要再跟那孩子谈谈，看上去不错
I'm gonna talk to the kid again.Seems nice.
你不能
You can'T.
为什么？,他说不喜欢我了么？
Why? Did he say he doesn't like me?
麻醉师告诉父母你干什么了
The anesthesiologist told the parents what you did.
每个人都是告密者
Everyone's a tattletale.
你儿子抑郁么?
Is your son depressed?
不，你是谁?
No,who are you?
我是豪斯医生
I'm dr. House.
哦，你就是那个白痴……
Oh,you're the idiot who--
我在走廊都听见了他的叫声
I heard him screaming all the way down the hallway.
如果我不叫醒他,就无法知道什么导致撞车
If I didn't wake him up,I wouldn't have learned what caused the crash.
我想他抽筋了
I think he had a seizure.
这不是我的错?
Th-this wasn't my fault?
如果他没有脑部问题,他就不会被烧了
Well,if he hadn't had the brain problem,he wouldn't have the burns.
换个说法,如果你没让他坐卡丁车
On the other hand,if you hadn't put him on the atv,
他也不会被烧
he also wouldn't have the burns.
你可以等我走了再争辩你的责任
You can debate your personal responsibility after I leave.
我得把他再次唤醒
I need to wake him up again.
我需要知道他是否服用抗抑郁药
I need to know if he's taking anti-depressants.
他没有
He's not.
他是我知道的最快乐的孩子
He's the happiest kid I know.
但你不知道，是吧?
But you don't know,do you?
他是我儿子
He's my son.
嗯，那也是我的意思
Mmm,that's sort of my point.
到了16岁，他们会告诉任何人,任何事，可不是父母
At 16,they'll tell anyone anything.Except their parents.
亚当跟我们无话不谈
Adam talks to us about everything.
对，我知道大麻和可卡因的事
Yeah,I know about the pot and the cocaine.
根本没有可卡因
There was never cocaine--
你肯定?
you sure?
你跟踪他么?
You having him followed?
他告诉我们在舞会喝醉的事
He told us when he got drunk at a party.
他告诉我们性交的时间
He told us when he started having sex.
16岁，东西多呢
16,way to go.
他告诉我们数学考试作弊的事
He tolus when he cheated on a math test.
他告诉我们女友欺骗他的事
He told us when his girlfriend cheated on him.
他跟我们从不隐瞒
He doesn't hide anything from us.
但如果他抑郁?
But if he was depressed?
他会告诉我们
He'd tell us.
我们不评论，他不抑郁,我们肯定
We don't judge. He's not depressed,we're sure.
"以他的生命打赌" 肯定?
"Bet his life on it" sure?
假设
Just hypothetically.
好
Okay.
孩子很快乐、快乐
Kid's happy.Happy,happy,happy.
那我们就回到开始，抽搐失调
Then we're back to where we started,seizure disorders.
抽搐失调不会导致高潮
Seizure disorders aren't causing orgasms.
脉管畸形
Vascular malformations.
语图上会看到
Would've seen it on the sonogram.
肝脑病?
Hepatic encephalopathy?
肝酶测试正常
Liver enzyme tests were normal.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
撒尿
Take a leak.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
不能进来，你们没消毒
Can't come in here.You're not sterile.
别碰我们的儿子，我们告诉你了
Don't touch our son,we told you.
认真的,你身上有成千上万的细菌病毒
Seriously,millions of bacteria,microbes on you.
他会死于脓血症
He'll die of sepsis.
如果你进去...
If you go in there...
我看他会再次把他唤醒
I think he's gonna wake him up again.
我知道他会
I know he is.
豪斯，你不能那么做
House,you can't do this.
如果每次我听见都有硬币的话
Oh,if I had a nickel for every time I've heard that.
放松，他们会诉我们么?
Relax. They gonna sue us?
如果我对了，我会挽救他的性命
If I'm right,I save his life.
如果我错了，他无论如何都会死
If I'm wrong,he's dead no matter what I do.
任何一条路,我到底对他们有多大伤害?
Either way,how much have I really hurt them?
别碰他
leave him alone!
你没消毒，你想杀他么?
You're not sterile. You wanna kill the kid?
给我注射器
Give me the syringe.
没有疼痛，就没有收获
No pain,no gain.
嘿，你给我停止
Hey,you gotta stop this.
你是对的，他不是抑郁
You're right. He's not depressed.
对，是啊
Yeah,sure.
我不会让你走除非你给我注射器
I'm not letting you go until you give me that syringe.
他手腕上是什么?
What's that on his wrist?
烧伤
a burn.
为什么是手腕?
Why on his wrist?
为什么不是手腕?
Why not on his wrist?
他的后辈，一切都乱套了
His back,his torso,everything's a mess.
他的前臂是干净的，除了这里
His forearms are clean. Except right there.
那又怎么了?
so what?
是个完整的圆环
It's a perfect circle.
汽油掉下来，atv的螺丝
So a drop of burning gasoline fell on his wrist. A screw from the atv.
或许
Maybe.
你干嘛折磨他?
Why are you torturing him?
你儿子抽烟么?
Does your son smoke?
我会杀了他
I'd kill him.
那么说他跟你谈性、吸毒,任何事但不说吸烟
So he talked to you about sex,crack.Anything except cigarettes.
他的手腕上有香烟烫伤
He has a cigarette burn on his wrist.
也有尼古丁痕迹在两个手指上
And also a fading nicotine stain between two fingers.
坏消息，你儿子有个肮脏不洁的习惯
Bad news,you son has a filthy,unhealthy habit.
好消息，他正要戒,坏消息，戒烟要了他的命
Good news,he's trying to quit.Bad news,the quitting's killing him.
好消息，我可以治好他,坏消息……没了，结束
Good news,I can cure him. Bad news... nope,that's the end of it.
戒烟会杀人?
Quitting smoking can kill?
戒烟药是抗镇静剂
No-smoke meds are anti-depressants.
从网络上来的破烂玩意
The crappy ones you get over the internet.
他们装上任何便宜的抗镇静剂
They're loaded with whatever anti-depressants they can get cheap.
父母肯定不带他去看儿科医生...
Since mommy and daddy obviously didn't take him to a pediatrician...
抱歉我说他抑郁错了
sorry,I was wrong about him being depressed.
治疗他吧
Treat him.
嘿，你滴酸了么?
hey.Did you drop acid?
我干嘛要那样?
Why would I do that?
滋扰我，或你很悲惨
To annoy me.Or maybe because you're miserable.
或者你要自毁，自己选吧
Or because you wanna self-destruct. Pick one.
如果是酸最早被大脑吸收
How 'bout because lsd acts on serotonin receptors in the brain,
可以治偏头疼如何？
which can stop a migraine in its tracks.
我说这也是可能性
I'm just saying it's also a possibility.
你怎么知道……
How did you know--
卡麦伦担心你
cameron is worried about you.
我告诉她第一次要等上12个小时
I told her that lsd lasts up to 12 hours.
如果你还能运行，那她一定错了
If you were functional,she must be wrong.
不那样，我也会吃一大堆抗镇静药
Either that,or I also took a whole bunch of anti-depressants,
然后可以替代
which short-circuited the lsd.
我是说那样也是个解释
I'm just saying that would also explain it.
谢谢你毁了我的临床试验
Thank you for ruining my clinical trials.
制药公司关闭了试验
Pharmaceutical company's shutting me down.
你开玩笑，真的?
You're kidding,really?
那怎么能让你惊奇呢?
How could that surprise you?
你给他们发了有关我数据的投诉信
You sent them an email complaining about my math.
告诉他们你的绝技
Telling them about your stunt.
我并不知道人们真的看邮件
I didn't know people actually read emails.
删除键很容易触摸
Delete button is so conveniently located--
那么接下来呢?
so what's next?
你会终生追踪我，折磨我?
You gonna follow me my whole life,torture me?
我干嘛那样?
Why would I do that?
你等了20年干这个，下面干嘛?
You waited 20 years to do this. What's next?
毁掉我的婚姻么?
Break up my marriage?
不，我们扯平了
No. We're even.
是啊
Right.
哦，谢谢陷害我
Oh,thanks for setting me up.
以眼还眼，还有抗抑郁药,全都平衡了
Eye for an eye,lsd,and antidepressants,everything in balance.
佛教叫它因缘，基督教称为黄金规则,犹太教……
Buddhists call it karma,christians call it the golden rule,jews call it...
我不知道，席勒拉比说计算让人痛苦
I don't know.Rabbi hillel said mething poignant.
宇宙总留下轨迹
Universe always settles the score.
是吗?
Does it?
不，但会的
No.But it should.
你真认为你能看到他并且不怨恨我?
do you think you'll ever be able to look at him and not blame me?
是，你呢?
Yeah. Will you?
我是宝拉
I'm paula.
嘿，宝拉
Hey,paula.
你怎么样?
How you doing?
你在大学工作？还是你全职……
You work over at the college? Or are you full time over at--
我在找乐子
I'm looking for a distraction.
你不需要谈话，对么?
You don't need to talk to do that,do you?